CONTACT INFORMATION Rm 614, Kelvin Building University of Glasgow Glasgow, G12 8QQ United Kingdom Work: +44 (0)14133 08855 Web: www.pauljwright.co.uk Email: paul.wright@glasgow.ac.uk Publication List: SAO/NASA ADS

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My interests range from stellar to solar physics; my main interests lie in the heating of the solar atmosphere, including active regions and loops. I have expertise in the analysis of spectroscopic and narrowband Extreme Ultra-Violet (EUV) and X-ray data from the *SDO*, and *Hinode* satellites, in addition to the hard X-ray (HXR) imaging/spectroscopic observations from *NuSTAR*'s heliophysics campaign. Furthermore, I am currently investigating the modelling of coronal light-curves using the EBTEL (Enthalpy Based Thermal Evolution of Loops) hydrodynamic code with particular interest in the weak bremmstrahlung components.

EDUCATION

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK

2014 – present (expected 2018)

Ph.D. Solar Physics

Thesis Topic: *The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings* Advisers: Dr Iain G. Hannah, Dr Alexander MacKinnon

University of Southampton, Southampton, UK

2010 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

First-class honours (1:1) Adviser: Professor Malcolm Coe

Harvard University/Harvard-Smithsonian CfA, Cambridge, MA, USA

2013 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

Thesis Topic: Superflare Rates of Solar-Like Stars Advisers: Dr Steven H. Saar, Dr Jeremy J. Drake

CURRENT ACADEMIC APPOINTMENT

APPOINTMENTS

PREVIOUS ACADEMIC

Affiliate Staff Member, University of Glasgow SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

2017 – present

Post-Graduate Research Assistant, University of Glasgow

2014 - 2017

SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

Project: The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings

- Analysed observations of the Sun with *NuSTAR*, a telescope not designed for heliophysics. These observations are the most sensitive of their kind and have resulted in numerous, wide-ranging highly-collaborative peer-reviewed publications.
- Analysed non-flaring coronal time-series in pursuit of signatures of the coronal heating mechanism. Techniques included time-lag analysis (cross-correlation), Fourier analysis, wavelet analysis, and local intermittency measure (LIM).
- Studied the temperature distribution of the solar atmosphere through the recovery of an ill-posed inverse problem (the differential emission measure, DEM) using techniques such as Tikhonov regularisation, Markov-Chain Monte Carlo, and sparsity.
- The press-release image produced from the *NuSTAR* observations obtained for Wright *et al.* 2017 was published by numerous news outlets, and is one of the five iconic images from *NuSTAR*'s first five years in space.

Collaborators: Dr Iain Hannah, Dr Alexander MacKinnon

Visiting Researcher, NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC)

2016

Heliophysics Science Division

• Worked on the possibility of implementing DEM maps in the Helioviewer project, and their usefulness as an input for various established analysis techniques.

Collaborators: Dr Nicholeen Viall, Dr Jack Ireland

Research Scholar, Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics (CfA)

2013 - 2014

Solar and Stellar X-Ray Group

- Designed and implemented a sophisticated stellar flare detection routine for long-cadence (30 mins) *Kepler* data obtained from a proprietary set of spectroscopically verified solar-type stars in three open clusters.
- A preliminary version of this work had coverage by Science, and The Smithsonian Magazine.

Collaborators: Dr Steven Saar, Dr Søren Meibom, Dr Jeremy Drake, Dr Vinay Kashyap

REFEREED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS	[1] Marsh, A. J., Smith, D. M., Glesener, L. et al 2017. First NuSTAR Limits on Quiet Sun Hard X-Ray Transient Events, ApJ (accepted)		
	[2] Wang, J., Simões, P. J. A., Jeffrey, N. L. S. et al 2017. Observations of Reconnection Flows in a Flare on The Solar Disk, ApJL, 847, L1		
	[3] Wright, P. J. , Hannah, I. G., Grefenstette, B. W., et al 2017. Microflare Heating of a Solar Active Region Observed with NuSTAR, Hinode/XRT, and SDO/AIA, ApJ, 844, 132		
	[4] Kuhar, M., Krucker, S., Hannah, I. G., et al 2017. Evidence of Significant Energy Input in the Late Phase of a Solar Flare from NuSTAR X-ray Observations, ApJ, 835, 6		
FIRST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS IN PREPERATION	[5] Wright, P. J., Hannah, I. G., Viall, N. M., et al		
	[6] Wright, P. J., Saar, S. H., Meibom, S., et al		
Conferences, Workshops, & Schools	Invited Oral Presentations ISSI Team Meeting: Coronal Nanoflares, Bern, CH Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, Cambridge, MA, USA	2016 2014	
	Oral/ePoster Presentations Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA Coronal Loops Workshop VIII, Palermo, Sicily, IT Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA Hinode 10, Nagoya, JP National Astronomy Meeting 2016, Nottingham, UK Hinode 9, Belfast, UK Glasgow-Cambridge Flare Workshop, Glasgow, UK	2017 2017 2016 2016 2016 2015 2015	
	Poster Presentations European Solar Physics Meeting (ESPM), Budapest, HU Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA Coronal Loops Workshop VII, Cambridge, UK NAM 2015, Llandudno, UK 223rd AAS Meeting, National Harbor, MD, USA	2017 2017 2016 2015 2015 2014	
	Schools Attended CESRA Radio Summer School 2015, Glasgow, UK STFC Advanced Summer School in Solar Physics, Dundee, UK	2015 2014	
	Conferences/Workshops Attended NuSTAR Heliophysics Workshop (remote participation), Berkeley, CA, USA SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK RAS Discussion Meeting: Results from IRIS, London, UK SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK 1st Space Glasgow Research Conference, Glasgow, UK	2017 2015 2015 2014 2014	
AWARDS AND GRANTS TOTAL: £7000	University of Glasgow Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Student Poster Award Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Studentship Award Coronal Loops Workshop VIII Travel Award National Astronomical Observatory of Japan Travel Award Hinode 9 Travel Award European Space Agency/Cambridge Philosophical Society Travel Award	2017 2017 2017 2016 2015 2015	
	Harvard University/Harvard-Smithsonian CfA 223rd AAS Travel Grant	2014	
	University of Southampton Research Scholarship Summer Studentship Grant	2014 2013 2013	

TEACHING

University of Glasgow

TEACHING	Astronomy 1 Tutorial Demonstrator	2016 - 2017
		2010 - 2017
	Supervised students, and marked first-year astronomy problem sets.	2015 2016
	Astronomy 3/4 (Honours) Laboratory Demonstrator	2015 - 2016
	Demonstrated, supervised, and marked a number of final-year research project	ts covering topics
	such as asteroid light curves, and solar limb darkening.	
	Physics Pre-University Summer School	2015
	Taught at a pre-university school for students entering first year.	
MEMBERSHIPS	NuSTAR Heliophysics Working Group, Member	2015 – present
	International Space Science Institute (ISSI), Young Scientist Member	2015 – present
	Member of Paola Testa's ISSI Team: New Diagnostics of Particle Acceleration	in Solar Coronal
	Nanoflares from Chromospheric Observations and Modeling	
	Royal Astronomical Society, RAS Fellow	2014 – present
	•	1
COMMUNITY	Nature Communications, Reviewer	2017 – present
INVOLVEMENT	Glasgow Astronomy & Astrophysics Group Meeting, Organiser	2017 – present 2017
INVOLVEMENT	CESRA Radio Summer School, Volunteer Organiser	2017
	CESKA Radio Summer School, volunteer Organiser	2013
_		
SCIENTIFIC	Glasgow Science Centre, Demonstrator	2016
OUTREACH	British Science Week, Demonstrator	2016
	Institute of Physics: Women and Girls in Science, Demonstrator	2016
	Scottish Television (STV), Guest Presenter	2015
	World Wide Telescope, Ambassador	2013 - 2014
	BBC Stargazing Live, Demonstrator	2013
	So'ton Astrodome, Demonstrator	2012
	BBC Bang Goes The Theory Roadshow, Demonstrator	2012
	UK Solar Physics (UKSP) Nuggets, concise, easy-to-read science articles	
	84. The first <i>NuSTAR</i> microflare	2017
		2017
	Hinode/XRT Picture of the Week (XPOW)	
	The First Microflare Observations with <i>Hinode/XRT & NuSTAR</i>	2017
PERSONAL	ColourBlind, A repository for colour-blind-friendly colour tables.	Citations: 1
PROJECTS		
Professional	Coursera, Inc. (MOOC Platform)	
DEVELOPMENT	Using Coursera.org, a massive open online course (MOOC) platform, to take specialize	vations (a series of
DEVELOFMENT	related courses and a final capstone project) offered by accredited universities to further	
	understanding in a wide range of computer science topics.	develop skills alld
	understanding in a wide range of computer science topics.	
	Data Science, Johns Hopkins University	2017 – present
	Nine-course (plus capstone) introduction to data science.	2017 – present
	Mastering Software Development in R, Johns Hopkins University	2017 – present
	Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing riguourous training in R.	2017 – present
	Statistics with R , Duke University	2017 present
	·	2017 – present
	Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing further training in R, with a	mphasis on statis-
	tics.	2017 mmasant
	Big Data, UC San Diego	2017 – present
	Five-course (plus capstone) introduction to big data using Hadoop with MapR	educe, Spark, Pig
	and Hive.	2017
	Machine Learning, University of Washington	2017 – present
	Three-course (plus capstone) introduction to Machine Learning.	2017
	Graphic Design, CalArts	2017 – present
	Four-course (plus capstone) introduction the fundamental skills required to n	nake sophisticated
	graphic design.	

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Computing: C, Python, R (caret, ggplot2, knitr), SQL, CRAN, IDL, LaTeX, git, GitHub, Hadoop (MapReduce, Spark, Pig, Hive), Linux/Unix, Mac OSX, Microsoft Windows, Bash, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Keynote, Wordpress, Shiny, GoogleVis, and Plotly, HTML, CSS, Javascript

General: Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Interdisciplinary Collaboration, Public Speaking, Statistics, Teaching, Writing (Technical & Lay)

MORE Information More information and auxiliary documents can be found at http://www.pauljwright.co.uk, on Research-Gate, and GitHub.